because I saw this thing the other day
this person texts an equation to
somebody and gets blocked for it that is
not cool it's 5 over 4X plus 3 equals
five over four X plus five over three I
wonder if we solve this thing if x will
have some secret message in it like this
expression here that when you erase the
top it says I love you let's bring this
piece down here I don't like fractions
so I want to get rid of all these
denominators in order to get rid of this
three I'm going to multiply everything
on both sides of the equation by three
and then to get rid of this 4X I'm going
to multiply everything on both sides of
the equation by 4X and then to get rid
of the 4X plus 3 I'm going to multiply
everything on both sides the equation by
4X plus 3. these threes will cancel this
4X and this 4X will cancel and this 4X
plus 3 will cancel with this 4X Plus 3.
on this left hand side 3 times 5 is 15
and 4x times 15 is 60x and on the right
hand side 5 times 3 is 15 and this 15
will distribute to both of these to give
us 60x plus 45 and then 5 times 4X is
20x and then 20x will distribute to 4X
plus 3 to give us 80x squared plus 60x
and now we can combine like terms by
adding these together so we have 80x
squared plus 120x plus 45. so now we
have a quadratic so let's set it equal
to zero let's subtract 60x from both
sides we have 0 on the left hand side
and then on the right hand side we have
80x squared plus 60x plus 45. we can
simplify this a bit all these
coefficients are divisible by 5. so
let's divide everything by five that
gives us 0 equals 16x squared plus 12x
plus 9. and in order to solve this let's
use the quadratic formula a is this
first coefficient B is the second
coefficient and C is the third
coefficient B here is equal to 12 so
we'll plug in 12 for both these B's a is
equal to 16 so we'll plug in 16 for both
the A's and C is equal to 9 so we'll
plug in 9 for the C 12 squared is equal
to 144 4 times 16 is 64 and 64 times 9
is 576. and 144 minus 576 is equal to
negative 432. and we can pull the
negative out of this to give us square
root of negative 1 times square root of
432 and this square root of negative 1
is going to be the imaginary number I
inside of the square root the 432 can be
broken out into 144 times 3 and we can
give each of these numbers their own
square root and square root of 144 is
equal to 12. so in the numerator we have
negative 12 plus or minus 12i root 3.
and in the denominator we have 2 times
16 which is 32. now all these
coefficients have a 4 in common this 12
can change into 4 times 3 this 12 can
change into 4 times 3 and the 32 can
change into 4 times 8 and then we can
cancel out all these fours and then we
don't want to mix this real portion and
this imaginary part inside of a fraction
so we'll split it up into two separate
fractions so the solution to this
equation is x equals negative 3 8 plus
or minus 3 I root 3 over 8. so let's put
a box around it I don't see a secret
message in here that's probably why they
got blocked